We're off to see the Wizard, the wonderful Wizard of Oz!
The Wizard of Oz is a adventure, fantasy, family
film directed by Victor Fleming.
Young Dorothy finds herself in a magical world where she makes friends with a lion, a scarecrow and a tin man as they make their
way along the yellow brick road to talk with the Wizard and ask for the things they miss most in their lives.
The Wicked Witch of the West is the only thing that could stop them.
Dorothy Gale, played by Judy Garland.
"Hunk" / Scarecrow, played by Ray Bolger.
"Hickory" / Tin Man, played by Jack Haley.
"Zeke" / Cowardly Lion, played by Bert Lahr.
Professor Marvel / The Wizard of Oz, played by Frank Morgan.
Miss Gulch / Wicked Witch of the West, played by Margaret Hamilton.
The Wizard of Oz is a 1939 American musical fantasy
film produced by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer.
Based on the 1900 novel The Wonderful Wizard of Oz by L.
Frank Baum, it was primarily directed by Victor Fleming, who left
production to take over the troubled Gone with the Wind.
The screenplay is credited to Noel Langley, Florence Ryerson, and Edgar
Allan Woolf, but includes contributions from other writers.
The film stars Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Jack Haley,
Bert Lahr, Billie Burke, and Margaret Hamilton.
The music was composed by Harold Arlen and adapted by Herbert
Stothart, with lyrics by Edgar "Yip" Harburg.
The film is celebrated for its use of three-strip Technicolor, fantasy
storytelling, musical score, and memorable characters.
It was a critical success and was nominated for five Academy Awards, including Best Picture, winning Best Original Song for
"Over the Rainbow" and Best Original Score for Stothart; an Academy Juvenile Award was presented to Judy Garland.
It was on a preliminary list of submissions from the studios for an
Academy Award for Cinematography (Color) but was not nominated.
While it was sufficiently popular at the box office, it failed to make a profit until its 1949 re-release, earning
only $3 million on a $2.7 million budget, making it MGM's most expensive production at the time.
The 1956 television broadcast premiere of the film on
CBS reintroduced it to the public.
According to the U.S.
Library of Congress, it is the most seen film in cinematic history.
In 1989, it was selected by the Library of Congress as one of the first 25 films for preservation in the United
States National Film Registry for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
It is also one of the few films on UNESCO's Memory
of the World international register.
It was ranked second in Variety's inaugural 100 Greatest
Movies of All Time list published in 2022.
It was among the top ten in the 2005 British Film Institute (BFI) list of 50 Films to be Seen by the Age of 14
and is on the BFI's updated list of 50 Films to be Seen by the Age of 15 released in May 2020.
It has become the source of many quotes referenced
in contemporary popular culture.
It frequently ranks on critics' lists of the greatest films in history and is
the most commercially successful adaptation of Baum's work.
The film explores themes of witch, adolescence, dreams,
based on novel or book, secret identity.
The tone is mind_bending.